（ナレーション）＜西暦２１９９年＞
＜地球は
ガミラスとの戦いに敗れ→
人類滅亡まで
あと１年と迫っていた＞
＜国連宇宙軍は　ひそかに
恒星間宇宙船　ヤマトを開発＞
＜大マゼラン銀河にある惑星
イスカンダルに→
地球環境の再生システムを
受け取りに行くのである＞
＜宇宙戦艦ヤマトは　ついに→
１６万８０００光年の
大航海へと旅立った＞
Pluto
Yamato, do you read?
（森雪の声）ヤマト　聞こえますか!?
メーデー　メーデー！
Mayday! Mayday!
I understand.
（ゲール）なるほど。
テロンの艦はヤマトというのか。→
So the Teron ship is called the Yamato.
しかし　なんとも　醜い艦だな。→
However...
What an ugly ship that is. Not a bit of grace to it!
美しさのかけらもない。
（シュルツ）ヤマトは　おそらく
このプラートに来るでしょう。→
The Yamato is probably on its way here, to Plat.
引き付けたうえ
ここで　たたきます。
We'll lure it in and destroy it.
（ゲール）ヤツが
プラートに来るという保証はあるのか。
Is there any guarantee they'll come here?
（シュルツ）彼らの星を　あのような姿に
変えた遊星爆弾は→
The planet bombs that turned their planet into a red husk
ここから発射されているのです。
were launched here.
なるほど。
では　見事　葬ってみせろ。
I see. Then this is a splendid chance for your inferior race,
これは
肌の色が違う　劣等氏族の貴様が→
of differently colored skin, to demonstrate your loyalty to Gamilas.
ガミラスへの忠誠を示す
絶好の機会だぞ。
（シュルツ）帝国への忠誠心では→
We're every bit as loyal to the Empire as pure-blooded Gamilans!
純血ガミラスの方々に
引けは取りません。
がはははっ！　それでこそ
栄えある　大ガミラスの軍人だ。
That's what I want to see in a great Gamilas soldier.
期待しているぞ。
ガーレ・デスラー！　総統　万歳！
I shall expect results. Garle Dessler!
Hail to our leader!
（シュルツ）総統　万歳！→
I long for those days when I fought for General Domel.
ドメル将軍のもとで
戦っていた頃が→
懐かしいな。
（ヤレトラー）はい。
Indeed.
（シュルツ）
定期便の方は　どうなっている？
How is the scheduled strike coming?
（ガンツ）遊星爆弾　１０３号が
間もなく　定刻発射いたします。
Planet bomb 103 will launch shortly.
（砲兵・通信　ガミラス語で）
Reflecting satellite 4. Deploying reflector.
Correcting angle +5 degrees.
Reflecting satellite 8. Deploying reflector.
Correcting angle +4 degrees.
（砲兵）
目標　誤差修正　マイナス３．７。
Correct for target errors -3.7.
Target sighted. Reflecting Satellite Cannon charging.
（砲兵）照準　目標捕捉。
反射衛星砲　エネルギー装填。
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]（砲兵）薬室内　圧力上昇中。
Chamber pressure rising.
（砲兵）反射衛星砲　発射準備　完了。
Reflecting Satellite Cannon charging complete.
（ヤレトラー）発射！
Fire!
ピシューーン!!
（砲兵）１０３に　着弾します。
Hitting 103.
（砲兵）
１０３の点火を確認。　角度良好。
103 has been ignited. Angle proper.
速度１７ガットで加速中。
Accelerating at a speed of 17 gat.
103 is on a collision course for planet Teron.
（砲兵）１０３　惑星テロンへの
コリジョンコースに入ります。
Don't you think we could use this?
これは　使えると思わないか？
（ガンツ）はっ？
ふふふっ。
（百合亜）
エッジワースカイパーベルトの→
Edgeworth-Kuiper belt object EKB 637 has deviated from its course.
ＥＫＢＯ６３７が
軌道を外れました。→
It's a planet bomb.
遊星爆弾です。
（沖田十三）悪魔め…。
（百合亜）現在→
Demons.
No enemies within two light-seconds of us.
本艦周辺　２光秒内に　敵影なし。
（太田）
へえ～　森さんの交代要員か？
So you're standing in for Mori?
いや～　潤うねぇ。
Nice to have another pretty girl around...
Stop staring. It's rude.
（島）ジロジロ見るな。　失礼だぞ。
（太田）でへっ！
そういや
真田副長と　古代さんも非番かぁ。
Then XO Sanada and Kodai are both off duty now, huh?
They're at the lab, looking at that Gamilas soldier.
例のガミラス兵のことで
解析室に行かれています。
Ah... Mori's there too then.
（太田）ああ～　森さんも　そっちね。
どうだい？　その席は。
How does it feel to sit there?
（南部）も…　問題ないよ。
I-It's fine...
（新見）すごいテクノロジーだわ。→
This technology is amazing.
この人工オルガネラは
ナノマシンで構成されてます。
Nanomachines comprise this artificial organelle.
Do you know the composition of its epidermis?
（真田）
体表組織は　なんだか分かるか？
（ＡＵ０９）表面構造ハ→
The exterior is composed of soft tektite rubber.
軟性テクタイトラバーデ
構成サレテイマス。
They're a race of machines?
（古代進）
ヤツらは　機械生命体だったのか。
Why do you think that?
（真田）なぜ　そう思うんだい？
えっ？　なぜって…。
Why? Then what are these?
じゃあ
こいつら　一体　何なんですか？
（真田）アンドロイドだ。
そんなことは分かってますよ！
Androids.
I already knew that!
（新見）これが
自己増殖する機械生命体なのか→
We can't say whether they're self-replicating machines,
ヒューマノイド種族を模倣した
単なる兵器なのかは→
or simply weapons modeled after humanoid life.
断定できないよ…　と
副長は　おっしゃっているんです。
That's what the XO means.
（真田）ありがとう。
いや　だったら…。
Thank you.
- But...
では　報告も終わりましたので
これで失礼します。
- Now then,
- But...
our report's over, so we'll be going.
おい！
文句　言わない。　さあ。
Hey...
No complaints... Go!
（真田）ユキカゼに
生存者がなかったのは→
You're sure there were no survivors aboard the Yukikaze, right?
間違いないんだね？
はい。
Yes.
（真田）そうか…　ありがとう。
Very well.
Thank you.
失礼します。
Excuse me.
（新見）気になさっていたんですね
先生。→
You're concerned about him. Aren't you, sir?
I quite like that about you...
そういうの嫌いじゃありません。
Which of them is the android?
どっちが　アンドロイドだか。
He's like, I dunno... A computer human! Or something.
こう…　なんていうか→
コンピューター人間！
って感じだよな。
That's just the way XO Sanada is.
真田副長は　ああいう方なのよ。
それにしてもさ…。
古代君。
Anyway...
Kodai.
何？
エンケラドゥスでは　ありがとう。
What?
Thanks for everything back at Enceladus.
えっ？
守ってくれたじゃない　私たちを。
You protected us.
それは　任務だから当然だよ。
Well, it was my mission. Of course I did.
Right, of course.
そうね。
そういえば　知ってたかい？
Oh, did you know? About the Cosmo Zero that came to help us.
あのとき
援護に来てくれたコスモゼロ→
主計科の山本ってヤツが
乗ってたらしいんだ。
Someone named Yamamoto, from accounting, piloted it.
Since when are you a pilot?
（加藤）
君は　いつから航空隊になった？→
今回は　大目に見るが
今度　あんなまねをしたら…。
I'll let it slide this time. But if you ever do that again...
It was the optimal course under those conditions.
（玲）あの状況下では
最善の判断でした。
くっ！
Let me transfer to the pilot squad.
航空隊に　転属させてください。
Are you going to try and avenge Akio?
明生の敵討ちでもするつもりか？
ダメだ!!
ガッ！
No!
俺に　その権限はない。　あるのは→
I have no right to decide that.
Only the captain does.
艦長だけだ。
Sometimes, you know...
（篠原）なんだかなぁ…。
（真琴）今度は　ロッカーですか？
A locker this time?
Yeah, she just won't listen.
まあな。　言うこと聞かねぇんだよ。
That sure is a stubborn locker...
（真琴）へえ～　ロッカーがね。
（佐渡）ふっ。
（真琴）加藤隊長！
（加藤）ん？
Lieutenant Kato!
Um, if that pilot hadn't come, it would've been really bad for us.
（真琴）あの…　この前
航空隊の人が来てくれなかったら→
私たち　かなり　やばかったです。
I think they saved our lives...
命の恩人かな…　なんて。
ふふっ　しゃあねぇか。
Oh, fine...
Um...
あの…。
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]（アナウンス）上級士官に通達。→
Attention all high-ranking officers.
上級士官は
中央作戦室に　集合してください。
All high-ranking officers, please meet in the main operations room.
（真琴）私　変なこと言いました？
Did I say something strange?
さあ？　わしゃ　知らんよ。
んん…　んん…。
Heck if I know!
ぶはははっ！
I had planned to avoid all unnecessary combat,
わしは　イスカンダルへの旅を
急ぐために→
無駄な戦闘は
極力　避けるつもりでいた。　だが→
to get us to Iscandar as soon as possible.
But we cannot allow the continued existence of the Pluto base,
地球を　あのような無残な姿に変え
今も　遊星爆弾を→
whose planet bombs have rendered the Earth a wasteland.
発射し続けている
冥王星基地だけは→
見過ごすわけにはいかない。
We shall destroy that base with everything we have.
我々は　全力で　この基地をたたく。
After the Gamilans captured Pluto, they altered its environment.
冥王星は
ガミラスに占領されて以来→
その環境が操作され
今や　海を擁する→
It is now a dwarf planet that has oceans.
準惑星に　変貌している。
国連宇宙軍では→
The UN Cosmo Force has analyzed the movement of surface hot spots,
地表の熱源反応の推移を
分析した結果→
これらのポイントの　どこかに
ヤツらの基地があると考えている。
and determined that the base is most likely to be at one of these points.
（相原）基地は
特定できていないんですか？
We can't identify it with certainty?
残念ながら。
（真田）おそらく→
Unfortunately not.
It's probable that they're using some kind of stealth shield around the base.
なんらかの遮蔽幕を展開し→
基地全体を
ステルス化しているのだろう。
They aren't making this easy...
（徳川）やっかいじゃな。
敵の本丸ですから→
It's a major enemy base. We can expect heavy resistance.
相当の抵抗が　予想されますね。
In terms of defense, we have the Wave Motion Shields.
我々にも
次元波動理論を応用した→
波動防壁という盾がある。
It will only function for twenty minutes.
有効時間は　２０分程度だが→
理論上は　敵の陽電子ビームにも
十分　対応できるはずだ。
But in theory, it should offer ample protection from enemy positron beams.
We'll launch the fighters before the Yamato breaches their warning zone.
ヤマトが
敵警戒宙域へ　突入する前に→
航空隊を発進させ
本艦は　囮となり→
The Yamato will act as a decoy,
要撃してくるであろう敵艦隊を
引き付けます。
to draw away the enemy fleet we're anticipating.
その間
航空隊は　ニクスの軌道を経て→
The fighters will set a course through Nyx's orbit,
カロンを迂回しつつ冥王星に降下。
around Charon, then down low, to search for the base.
低空での索敵行動に移り→
基地を発見しだい
これを　たたきます。
Once they find it, they will destroy it.
なお
ヤマトが　敵艦隊の包囲を突破→
Further, after the Yamato breaks through the enemy fleet,
冥王星沖合に達した後は→
and arrives off the coast of Pluto,
it will provide support fire from above, to cover the fighters.
上空からの艦砲射撃で
航空作戦を支援します。
I propose another plan.
（南部）意見具申します。
ロングレンジで　波動砲を使えば→
A long-range shot from the Wave Motion Gun
敵基地殲滅も容易です。
would destroy the base easily.
We will not use the Wave Motion Gun.
波動砲は使わない。
（南部）なぜです？→
Why not? It's a waste!
それじゃあ　宝の持ち腐れですよ！
Using it would destroy not only the base, but Pluto itself!
波動砲を使えば
敵の基地ばかりか→
冥王星そのものを破壊してしまう。
それは　できない。
I cannot do that.
Why not? What's a planet or two?!
いいじゃないか　星の１つや２つ！
南部君！
Nanba...
ダメだ!!
なっ…。
No!
戦術長が　ああ言ってんだから
いいじゃないか。
Listen to the Tactical Officer. Why not?
I'm telling you, this will keep the pilots from suffering any losses, as well.
（南部）僕は　君たち航空隊の損耗も
防げますよと言ってるんだ。→
そもそも　ヤマトに
航空隊が　必要なのかどうかは→
Of course, I don't know if the Yamato even needs a fighter squadron...
疑問だけどね。
なんだと？
What was that?
It's true!
本当のことだよ。
貴様！
Why, you...
やめんか！
うっ…。
Enough!
We will commence attack on Pluto without the Wave Motion Gun.
冥王星攻略は
波動砲を使わず行う。
これは　決定事項だ。
It's been decided.
Yes, sir.
（南部）はい…。
航空隊の指揮は→
Kodai, you are in charge of the fighter squadron.
古代　お前が執れ。
はっ…　自分がでありますか？
I-I am, sir?
そうだ。
Yes.
Yes, sir!
はい！　古代戦術長　航空隊の
指揮を執ります。
Tactical Officer Kodai will take command of the fighter squadron.
んん…。
作戦指揮は→
We will lead the operation from the combat bridge's CIC.
第二艦橋　戦闘指揮所で行う。
徳川君も　第二艦橋に上がって
機関を見てくれ。
Tokugawa, go to the combat bridge, and look over the engine.
分かりました。
Understood.
That will be all.
以上だ。
A moment.
ちょっと　よろしいでしょうか？
ん？
You're... Aren't you...
君は　確か…。
Yamamoto, from accounting. I won't take up much of your time.
主計科の山本です。
お手間は取らせません。
Yamamoto...
山本って…。
じゃあ　あのゼロは君が！
Then, you piloted that Zero?
航空団のエースだったか知らないが
がさつな男だよ→
I don't know if he's the pilot squad's ace, but that Kato's a jerk.
あの加藤ってヤツは。
あっ。
ん？　うわっ！
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]（アナウンス）第五分隊は　直ちに…。
（南部）ふ～ん→
Team 5 to hangar 1.
Oh, I see...
Repeat, Team 5 to hangar 1.
なるほどねぇ。
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]（アナウンス）第五分隊は　直ちに→
第一格納庫に集合。
Then, if you'll excuse me.
おう　島。
Oh, Shima!
Now you can avenge your brother.
これで
兄さんの敵討ちができるな。
やれることを　やるだけさ。
I'll do what I can, but that's it. Take care of the Yamato for me.
ヤマトの方は頼んだ。
コン　コン（ノック）
入れ。
Come in.
（島）島航海長　入ります。
It's Navigation Officer Shima.
We're almost at the mission zone. Please report to the CIC.
（島）間もなく　作戦宙域です。→
戦闘指揮所の方へ　お願いします。
Why did you come here?
わざわざ　どうした？
You're a hero of the Second Battle of Mars.
艦長は
第二次火星海戦の英雄であり→
And I have always admired you as a sailor.
船乗りとして憧れておりました。
I lost my father in these seas, where they first attacked us.
自分は　ヤツらが
先制攻撃を仕掛けた　この海で→
父を亡くしています。　ですから→
So I agree with your plan to attack Pluto.
冥王星をたたくという
艦長のお考えには　賛成です。→
航海長として　この後れは→
As Navigation Officer, I swear to make up for the lost time.
必ず　取り戻します。
そうか。
I see.
≫ピィーー（笛の音）
戦術長　作戦前に悪いが→
Tactical Officer, I realize the mission is about to commence,
ちょっと話があるんだ。
but I'd like to speak with you briefly.
Sure.
分かった。　だが　その前に→
But first, there's something I'd like you all to hear.
みんなに
聞いてもらいたいことがある。
本日付けで
主計科の１名を　戦術科航空隊に→
We have a transfer, from accounting to the fighter squadron.
転属させることになった。
えっ？
（一同）おお～！
あっ！
航空隊に　転属を命じられました
山本です。　よろしくお願いします。
I've been ordered to transfer into the fighter squadron.
My name is Yamamoto. Nice to meet you all.
ヒュ～　ヒュ～！（口笛）
（杉山）こりゃあ　やる気が→
I feel like working twice as hard now.
出てきたねぇ。
やる気ってなんだよ→
Working twice as hard at what, Sugiyama?
杉山。
（根本）歓迎するぞ！
Welcome to the club!
（加藤）玲！　お前…。
「アキラ」？
Akira! You...
Akira?
Aren't you Rei?
君　レイ君じゃ…。
失礼します。
Excuse me...
ピッ　ピッ
これで→
This name is read "Akira".
「アキラ」と読むんです。
そうか。
I see... I didn't realize.
俺は　てっきり…。
（玲）レイで　かまいません。→
Rei is fine. Everyone calls me that.
皆　そう呼びますから。
分かった。
All right.
≪ガタン（ドアの音）
ん？
皆　そう呼びますから。
分かった。
Captain Okita has already approved this.
この件は　艦長も了承済みだ。
≪ガタン（ドアの音）
ん？
では　失礼します。
この件は　艦長も了承済みだ。
んん…。　ったく…。
では　失礼します。
Jeez...
I'll be handling the pilot and fighter end of the operation.
本航空作戦は　自分が指揮する。
アルファが　北半球
ブラボーが　南半球を受け持ち→
Alpha will take the northern hemisphere.
Bravo, the southern hemisphere.
冥王星降下後は
２機編隊で　索敵行動に移る。
After the descent to Pluto,
we'll split into groups of two, to start the operation.
山本　君は　僕と同じアルファだ。
はい。
Yamamoto. You'll be in Alpha, with me.
Yes, sir.
ここには
家族や友人を　ヤツらの攻撃で→
I'm sure some of you have lost family and friends to enemy attacks.
失った者もいるだろう。
だが　刺し違えようなんて気は
起こすなよ。
But do not consider dying to avenge them.
Come back alive. That's an order!
必ず　生きて戻れ！
よし　行こう。
何か　話があったんじゃないのか？
You wanted to speak with me about something?
Nah, it's okay. No need to anymore.
いや　いい。　もう済んだよ。
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]（アナウンス）カタパルト要員は
発艦準備に備えよ。→
繰り返す。　カタパルト要員は→
発艦準備に備えよ。
加藤隊長→
Lt. Kato...
ご武運を。
（加藤）おう！
Good luck.
Right!
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]（アナウンス）
両舷　ハッチ開放準備に入る。→
誘導員は　配置に着け。
（玲・通信）古代一尉。→
Lieutenant Kodai.
Thank you for the transfer.
転属の件　感謝いたします。
I was impressed by your work on Enceladus.
エンケラドゥスで見せた
その腕を買ったんだ。
Don't die out there, Yamamoto.
死ぬんじゃないぞ　山本。
Yes, sir.
（玲）はい。
Lt. Kodai, go out and avenge Earth for us.
（通信）古代一尉
地球の敵を　取ってきてください。
We're almost to the mission zone.
（太田）間もなく　作戦宙域に入る。
（真田）波動防壁　展開。
（太田）波動防壁　展開。→
Deploy the Wave Motion Shields.
Deploying Wave Motion Shields.
出力８０％。
航空隊　発艦準備　完了。
Output at eighty percent.
Fighters ready for launch.
Initiating Operation M-2. Lower the Hayabusa!
メ２号作戦を発動する。
ハヤブサを降ろせ！
（管制員）コスモゼロ
アルファ１　アルファ２　発艦せよ。
Cosmo Zeros Alpha 1 and Alpha 2, you are cleared for takeoff.
アルファ１　ラジャー。
クリア　フォー　テイクオフ。
Alpha 1, roger. Clear for takeoff.
アルファ２　ラジャー。
クリア　フォー　テイクオフ。
Alpha 2, roger. Clear for takeoff.
（通信）
アルファ１より　各機。　これより→
Alpha 1 to all fighters.
Maintain radio silence until target is located. Activate ECM.
目標発見まで　通信管制を実施。
ＥＣＭ　起動。
成功を祈る！
Good luck out there.
Passing through Nyx's orbit.
（太田）
現在　ニクスの軌道を通過中。
It's so quiet... Is this really enemy space?
（島）静かだ…。
本当に　ここは敵地なのか？
Anything on the radar?
レーダーに反応は？
敵艦影　認められず。
No enemy ships sighted.
Maybe they were frightened of the Yamato?
敵さん
ヤマトに　おじけづいたかな？
いや　この静けさからは→
No, this silence feels more threatening.
逆に　脅威を感じる。
うむ…。　森→
Mori, keep a close eye on that radar.
引き続き　対空警戒を厳とせよ。
はい。
Yes, sir.
Captain, if we make it through Charon's orbit
艦長　このまま
カロン軌道を抜け→
and get Pluto in our sights, all we'd need is the Yamato...
冥王星を　直接
照準に　収められれば→
このヤマトだけで…。
本作戦の成否は→
This operation depends on our ability to work with the fighter squad.
航空隊との連携にある。
古代たちを待つんだ。
We'll wait for Kodai.
ドォーーン！
（一同）うわぁ～！
ん？　なんだ？　今の光。
What was that light?
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]　ウィン　ウィン　ウィン…（警報）
んん…　状況報告！
Report!
敵のロングレンジ攻撃と
思われます。
Probably an enemy long-range attack.
一体　どこから撃ってきたんだ!?
Where did they fire from?
敵艦影　確認できず。
冥王星からでもありません。
I'm not seeing any enemy ships. And that wasn't from Pluto.
Damage to deck 3. Wave Motion Shields penetrated.
第三デッキに　被弾！
波動防壁が　貫通されています。
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]（アナウンス）隔壁閉鎖。
Closing bulkheads!
ぎゃあ～！　なんじゃ？
なんじゃ？　なんじゃ？　えっ？
What's going on?
うわ～！　見ないでください！
白じゃ。
Please don't look!
Inertial control system is down!
（相原）
慣性制御システムがダウン。
艦内　０Ｇ状態です。
（太田）両舷スタビライザー　稼働。
Ship interior at zero-g.
The attack came from ten o'clock, port side.
攻撃は　左舷１０時の空間から
行われたもよう。
Begin evasive maneuvers.
回避行動に移れ。　取舵いっぱい。
Hard to port, and move into their blind spot.
発射予想地点からの死角へ入る。
回避行動に移る。
と～りか～じいっぱ～い！
Evasive maneuvers. Hard to port!
First shot has hit. Impact confirmed.
（兵士）初弾命中。　着弾を確認。
（兵士）
ヤマト　回避行動に移りました。
Yamato is engaging in evasive maneuvers.
Splendid, Commander Shultz...
お見事です　シュルツ司令。
このガンツも　まさか
遊星爆弾の発射システムを→
Even I, Ganz,
never imagined using the planet bomb launch system as a weapon!
武器として転用するとは
思いませんでした。
発想の転換だよ。　戦場では　常に→
You must consider things from different angles.
On the battlefield, the ability to adapt is always critical.
臨機応変さが　求められるのだ。
ドメル閣下の教えですね。
しかし→
General Domel taught us that.
However, it's unfortunate that the first strike didn't finish them.
初弾で沈められなかったのは
残念です。
狩りは　楽しみながらやるものだよ
ヤレトラー。
A hunt is something to be savored, Jarletora.
反射衛星砲　次弾装填！
Prepare reflecting satellites for next volley!
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]（砲術長・ガミラス語で）
Recharging energy! Quickly!
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]（砲兵・ガミラス語で）
40 seconds until energy charging complete.
Analysis of the attack's flight path puts this area in their blind spot.
弾道解析の結果　ここならば→
死角となります。
うむ。
はぁ～…。
助かったぁ。
We're safe...
Stay on guard.
気を緩めるな。　ヤツらは
ヤマトの位置を把握している。
They know where the Yamato is. They're sure to strike again.
必ず　また仕掛けてくる。
Maintain geostationary orbit.
静止軌道を維持。
There's a lot of debris.
（真田）デブリの数が多いな。
（シュルツ）それで隠れたつもりか？
Do you think yourselves hidden?
反射衛星　７号　１３号→
Reflecting satellites 7, 13, 28. Deploying reflectors.
２８号　リフレクター　展開。
反射衛星砲　発射～！
Fire Reflecting Satellite Cannon!
ピシューーン！
ドォーーン！
（一同）うわぁ～！
先ほどと同じ攻撃です。
It's the same attack as before.
死角だったんじゃないんですか!?
Wasn't this supposed to be a blind spot?
レーダー　どこからだ？
発射位置　特定できません。
Radar, where did the attack originate?
I can't find the launch point.
Maintain our position!
艦体を維持！
（島）ダメです…→
We can't... Propulsion's dropping. I can't control it!
推力が低下しています。
操舵不能！
被弾箇所から
作動流体が　流出しています。
We're leaking working fluid from the point of impact!
島　冥王星の海に　着水させるんだ。
は…　はい！
Shima, land us in the seas of Pluto.
Y-Yes, sir.
Raise the bow!
艦首　起こせ～！
（島）着水態勢に入る。
総員　衝撃に備え。
Preparing to land.
All crew, brace for impact.
（島）はぁ…　着水　完了。
気を抜くな！
Landing complete...
Stay on guard!
（島）はっ。
艦長　間もなく　波動防壁の→
Captain, we're approaching the Wave Motion Shields' time limit.
稼働限界時間を超えます。
今度　同じ攻撃を受けると…。
分かった。
One more of those attacks...
Understood. Have the ship repaired.
君は
艦の補修を急いでくれ。　相原→
Aihara, any word from the fighters?
航空隊からの連絡は？
まだ　ありません。
Nothing yet.
艦長。
ん？
Captain...
意見具申して
よろしいでしょうか？
May I make a suggestion?
（ガンツ）しぶといヤツめ。
Persistent bastards...
息つく暇を与えるな。
反射衛星砲　次弾装填！
Don't give them a chance to rest.
Ready next round from the Reflecting Satellite Cannon!
反射衛星　配置完了。
Reflecting satellites in position.
（兵士）
反射衛星砲　エネルギー装填　完了。
Reflecting Satellite Cannon charged.
（シュルツ）
ヤマトよ　お前は　よく戦った。
Yamato, you have fought well.
However, this is the end. Farewell, Yamato!
しかし　これで最後だ。
さらば　ヤマト！
ピシューーン！
高エネルギー体　真上です！
Powerful energy readings... Directly overhead!
Directly                Above
ドォーーン!!
Episode 5: The Trap on All Sides
The Yamato sinks into the Pluto Sea.
Yamato, rise...
Rise, Yamato!
The people of Earth await your return. It is their last hope.
Open the vents! Raise the Yamato!
Target the hidden enemy base,
and fire a shot into the aurora-filled skies!
Next time: The Sun Sets on Pluto.
There are 361 days left before humanity is extinct.
ミスタープロ野球、長嶋茂雄さん
と
日米で活躍した松井秀喜さんに、
国民栄誉賞が授与され、
２人の夢の始球式が実現した。